Let's explicitly define the terms dirty data and messy data.
首先让我们对“脏数据”和“杂乱数据”进行明确定义
To help with this, think of your data like your bedroom.
为便于理解 不妨把你的数据想象成你的卧室
Everyone wants clean data like everyone,
人人都想要干净有效的数据
or at least your mother wants a clean bedroom and this bedroom clearly isn't clean.
就像人人或者说至少母亲们总想拥有一间干净的卧室一样
It's both dirty and messy.
但这件卧室显然并不干净 既脏又乱
A dirty bedroom might have dirty plates and cutlery,
一间脏兮兮的卧室可能会有脏盘子和餐具
garbage like candy wrappers or banana peels,
还有像糖果纸或香蕉皮这样的垃圾
maybe even physical dirt tracked in from outside.
甚至有从户外带进来的脏东西
These don't belong in your bedroom.
这些都不属于你的卧室
The messy part of the bedroom are different.
卧室杂乱的部分则不同
Messiness is structural or organizational issues.
杂乱是结构性或组织性的问题
Think clothes in the ground,
想象一下卧室满地都是衣服的情景
clothes belong in your bedroom but not in the ground.
这些衣服属于你的卧室 但不应该放在地上
Or unmade bed, your bed should probably be made, that's messy.
或想象你的床凌乱不堪 而你本应该整理床铺的 这就是杂乱问题
And data can be thought of in the same way.
你可以用同样的方式来思考数据
Dirty data which has issues with its content is often called
内容有问题的脏数据通常被称为低质量数据
low quality data and can include things like inaccurate data,
其中可能包括不准确的数据
corrupted data and duplicate data.
损坏的数据和重复数据
Messy data on the other hand had issues with its structure.
另外一方面 杂乱数据通常都存在结构性问题
It is often referred to as untidy.
通常称其为不整洁
Tidy data means each variable forms a column,
整洁的数据是指每个变量构成一列
each observation forms a row and each type of observational unit forms a table.
每次观察构成一行 每类观察单元构成一个表格
Any other arrangement is messy which is the exact term that Hadley Wickham,
除此之外 其他任何排列都是杂乱的 这就是 Hadley Wickham 给出的确切定义
the inventor of the tidy data format uses in his tidy data paper.
Hadley Wickham 是整洁数据格式的创始人 他在有关整洁数据的论文中使用了这一术语
And again, here's what tidy looks like in comparison.
这就是整洁数据的例子 你可以对比一下
Just like you can clean your bedroom,
就像你可以打扫卧室一样
you can clean your data and it takes time and skill.
你也可以清理你的数据 这需要花点时间 并有一定技巧
Fortunately, programming tools like Python and its libraries can help us,
幸运的是 像 Python 以及它的类库这样的编程工具能够帮助我们
like a vacuum might help you vacuum up dirt,
就像真空吸尘器能帮你吸尘
or a dresser might help you organize your clothes.
衣柜能帮你整理衣服一样
Immaculately clean data is the goal and it's a beautiful thing once you have it.
完美地清理数据正是我们的目标 一旦你掌握它 就会发现这是一件非常美好的事